# HITESH BHATIA

New Delhi, India +91 9871983559 https://www.linkedin.com/in/hiteshbhatia3559@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Full time professional high frequency trader in the global Cryptocurrency markets, with an in depth understanding and four years of experience analyzing tick by tick data. Intensive experience in strategy and order execution analysis using large data sets in Python, and implementation of strategies in C# and C++ using propreitary institutional infrastructure and code templates.

Currently a part of the Quant effort at FalconX, with a focus on propreitary exchange market making, institutional liquidity provisioning and pricing, and +EV strategies that benefit from lower fees as a consequence of designated market making.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## QUANTITATIVE TRADER FALCONX REMOTE - BANGALORE

Apr 2021 - Present Delivered an improvement of 50% on PNL on market making volumes of over \$100M per week as part of the

Spot Designated Market Making program on Binance, using the Deltix ecosystem (Strategies in C# within

QuantOffice, using trades and orderbook data)

Implemented DEX volume reporting (for AMM client deliverables) Implemented automatic inventory managed on exchanges

Implemented custom alerting for trading algos (ranging from market making to client algos)

Provided market analysis and deep insights with data to the CEO and other higher ranking colleagues within the

firm

Designed software specs and implemented POCs for several trading products that are in use by the OTC trading

desk

#### QUANTITATIVE TRADER SMC GLOBAL SECURITIES NEW DELHI

Jan 2020 - March 2021 Implemented basis trading strategies in C++ with proprietory libraries developed in house

Performed data analysis of execution flow, strategy performance, latency statistics and risk, with vanilla Python

and visualisation in Jupyter Notebooks using Matplotlib/Plotly

Managed development of Market Data and Order Management System with two software developers on rotaa-

tion

Managed communication with partners as a SPOC for SMC to cryptocurrency exchanges

#### QUANTITATIVE ANALYST IRAGE CAPITAL MUMBAI

March 2019 - Jan 2020 Scrutinized high frequency tick by tick data programmatically, and generating analysis and improvements for

existing delta-1

strategies.

Traded a large variety of the Indian markets, primarily commodities (MCX) and Currencies (USDINR on NSE and

BSE)

Developed Quality-of-life programs that automatically analyze data on a periodic basis, removing the need for

manual analysis.

Hands-on experience in Pandas for analysis and other libraries for data manipulation and transportation for auto-

## DESIGNATED PARTNER POINT FIVE CAPITAL NEW DELHI

Nov 2018 - March 2019 Handled existing and onboarding new clients, raising INR 5M of funding

Developed manual profitable futures and options strategies Automated existing strategies, deployed to the Crypto market

(still manging personal wealth on these strategies)

## CYBER SECURITY ANALYST ERNST & YOUNG LLP AEROCITY

June 2018 - Oct' 2018

## **TECHNOLOGIES USED**

C++/C# - Four years of experience in writing strategies and studies on top of existing boilerplate templates on various libraries. Deriving and capturing insights about orderbook arrival rates and their effects on the market

PYTHON - Four years of experience, intermediate level competency. Libraries used- Pandas, Matplotlib, ta-lib, ccxt, redis, numpy, exchange libs like binance, Dash, Panels, AWS apis

PINESCRIPT - Time series analysis, alerts and indicators

LINUX - Operational understanding of linux file systems, commands and basic awk scripting (aided with commandline python), rudimentary understanding of Kubenetes

**ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS** 

B. TECH - IT

ADGITM

Aug' 2014 - Aug' 2018

GGSIP University, New Delhi